MOHD OMER.

6309656302

mohdomer2705@gmail.com

OBJECTIVE

Full Stack Developer with fresh year of experience. Dedicated to achieving all-round success, valuing diversification of experiences and skills. Embraces continuous personal growth through collaboration and learning, recognizing the importance of collective efforts in achieving greater milestones.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Communication Engineering (E.C.E), Osmania University

7.5 SCGPA

2020 - 2024

SKILLS

Frontend Development JavaScript, CSS, HTML, React

Backend Development Node.js, Mongoose, MongoDB, MySQL

Version Control Git, GitHub
APIs RESTAPI,
Deployment/Hosting Vercel, RENDER

Programming Languages
C, C++, Python, Java
Authentication and Authorization
JWT (JSON Web Tokens)

Core Subjects Database Management, Computer Networking, Computer Organization

Architecture, AIML introduction

EXPERIENCE

CODE CLAUSE WEB INTERN
Free Code Camp Full Stack Certification
NSIC Role Name - WEB Intern

FEB 2024 - March 2024 Jan 2023 - June 2023 Jan 2020 - feb 2020

PROJECTS

CORE PROJECTS

IOT COLOR SORTING MACHINE USING ARDUINO AND SENSORS ETC..

FRONTEND

1)News App using Full Stack: which may produce category wise news in cards and other please do visit my github or more!

Key Features

User Authentication

Customizable News Feed

Real-Time Updates

Responsive Design

Search Functionality

• HOSTING: http://https://github.com/REM02705

• GitHub REPO: https://vercel.com/remo2705s-projects/de-2-oyol

2) RESUME BUILDER

HOSTING: https://resumebuilder-psi-smoky.vercel.app/

GitHub REPO: http://https://github.com/REM02705

2)PERSONAL PORTFOLIO (css,html)

HOSTING: https://vercel.com/remo2705s-projects/codeclause-bdem

GitHub REPO: https://github.com/REMO2705/personal-portfolio

BACKEND

5) TOURISM APPLICATION

HOSTING: http://lgope-natours.onrender.com

GITHUB REPO:https://github.com/REM02705/BACK-END

Key Features

Authentication and Authorization, Credit card Payment Sign up, Log in, Logout, Update, and reset password.

User profile An admin user or a lead guide can edit any booking. Reviews

Only regular users can book tours (make a payment). Only regular users can write reviews for tours that they have booked.

users can not book the same tour twice. .

Short Project Title: Built a dance website for hosting events, made Notesibook using advanced concepts of React Native.

Short Project:

- 1) Built many small games using vanilla javascript
- 2) fitness website for gym
- 3)dance website for dance culb of our college

CERTIFICATIONS

FREECODECAMP:Responsive Web Design:

Coursera: Introduction to REACT by Meta

Coursera: Introduction to javascript by Meta

 $Udemy: Node. js, Mongodb, mongoose\ link: lgope-natours. on render. com\ the\ complete\ Bootcamp 2023$

NPTEL-Introduction to databasesystem-

SUNTEK INSTITUE-Programming in C,JAVA,PYTHON

VOLUNTEERING

Office Barrier for Students Chapter IEEE:

Involved in volunteering for the Office Barrier for Students Chapter IEEE.